好了好了 她来了
Okay, okay.Here she comes!
母亲节快乐 哇噢
Happy mother's day...oh!
你穿着这是什么东西
What are you wearing?
你不记得这件T恤了
You don't remember this shirt?
你还在上幼儿园时 你送我的母亲节礼物
You made it for me for mother's day in kindergarten.
-太可爱了 -太邪恶了
- It's adorable. - It's perverted.
感觉就像你被
It looks like you were felt up
-街角那个变态给骚扰了 -为什么是那个人
- By that creepy guy around the coner. - Ew! Why him?
只有他有双畸形的小手
'cause he's got, like, freakishly tiny hands.
别瞎说
Thank you!
真不敢相信你居然还留着这件T恤
I cannot believe you kept that shirt.
我当然会留着 我是你的母亲
Of course I kept it. I'm your mother.
你做的任何东西我都留着
I keep everything you make me.
求你脱下吧
Please take that off.
除非我死了
Oh, when I'm dead.
今天是我的节日
Today is my special day,
现在我品尝一下咖啡
And I am gonna enjoy me some coffee.
-你应该知道那是个笔筒吧 -现在知道了
- You know that's a pencil holder, right? - Oh, I do now.
你先来
Go first.
-不 你先来 -曼尼 别磨蹭了
- No, you can go first. - Manny, go first!
不要 杰 你先来
No, Jay, you go first.
别闹了 速度上缴礼物
Ah, somebody give me a present!
天啊 杰 钻石项链
Oh, Jay, a diamond necklace!
谢谢你
Thank you!
你应得的
You deserve it.
送吧 孩子
Go ahead, kid.
母亲节快乐 妈妈
Happy mother's day, mom.
果味麦圈项链
A necklace made of the froot loops!
我爱死它了
I love it!
我知道比不上钻石的 妈妈
I know they're not exactly diamonds, mom.
哪有 它们漂亮极了
No, they're beautiful.
等等 我要忏悔一下
You know what? I got a confession to make.
那些不是真的钻石 假的
Those aren't real diamonds. No.
还给我 回头我给你买真的
Here, give them back. I'll get you some real ones later.
该死 我也要澄清一下
Dang it. Now I got to come clean.
那些不是真的果味麦圈 是无厂家的伪劣产品
These aren't real froot loops. They're generic.
到手的鸭子都飞了
Now I have no presents again.
早上好
Good morning!
这是什么
Hey, what's this?
我知道你为了照顾莉莉 有时不得不晚睡
Well, I know you've had some late nights with Lily,
这是我向你表达爱意和谢意的方式
And this is just my way of saying "Thank you" And "I love you."
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
好戏才刚刚开始
And this is just the beginning.
没错 因为今天是你的节日
Yeah, 'cause today is your day.
今天
Today?
一整天哦
All day.
今天 今天是我的节日
Today. Today is my day.
感觉开始不对路了
Something's happening.
-今天是母亲节 -那又如何
- It mother's day, Mitchell. - So?
你在母亲节给我端上了这份丰盛的早餐
You're bringing me breakfast in bed on mother's day.
别这么想 这不是母亲节特供早餐
Okay, no, no, this is not a mother's day breakfast.
只是正好今天是母亲节
This is breakfast that happens to be on --
你把我看作是是莉莉的妈妈
You think of me as Lily's mother!
-当我是你的老婆 当我是女人 -你说什么
- I'm your wife! I'm a woman!! - What?
说实话 他这么责备我有点不爽
Honestly, I'm a little offended that he accused me of that.
实际上 我对那个话题十分敏感
I'm acally very sensitive to that issue.
好像我有把我的伴侣当成过女人一样
Like I would ever treat my partner as a woman.
貌似有人换了新窗帘哦
Somebody got new curtains.
没办法 普里契特夫人喜欢购物
Well, Mrs. Pritchett loves to shop.
看来6点之前是走不了了
Oh, we're never gonna be done by 6:00.
最好先打个电话回家
Better call home.
不然老婆会不高兴的
The wife's not gonna like this.
有时我觉得他就喜欢冲我发火
Sometimes I think he just wants to be mad at me.
-我吃不下 -好吧 随你便
- I can't eat! - Okay, you know what?
既然你不领我的情
If you can't accept the nice gesture,
那拉倒好了
Then just forget it.
那气球放起来 她正在闹别扭呢
Okay, scratch the balloons. She is in a mood.
我问克莱尔她母亲节想要什么
I asked claire what she wanted for mother's day,
她说"滚得远远的"
And she said, "Take a hike."
当然不是对我说的
It's not like that.
她只是痴迷于行走在大自然间
She's -- she's just bananas for walking around in nature.
所以 她和歌洛莉亚
Um, so, she and -- and gloria
带孩子们去大峡谷
Are taking the kids up the canyon
我和杰呢 就穿上围裙
Um,and jay and I are, uh, throwing on the aprons
为她们准备一个母亲节盛宴
And preparing a mother day feast.
这嘛
It's...
肯定会非常有趣
It's gonna be fun.
我知道你想要离我而去
I know you want to leave me
-可我不愿意 -厨房禁止杂耍
- But I refuse to -- - We're not doing that.
你应该知道这片树林里有狼出没吧
You know there are coyotes in these woods?
你带武器了吗
Did you pack a weapon?
我有跟拐杖
I have a walking stick.
它能当剑使吗
Does it become a sword?
我感觉它能变成助跑拐杖吧
I guess it could become a running stick.
好吧 你的意思是你能跑过
All right, you're gonna outrun a coyote?
世界上最快的哺乳动物土狼吗
The fastest mammal in the world?
我不确定我是否有这能耐
I'm not sure that's true.
那你要怎么用冰棍棒击退它们呢
And how are you gonna fend them off with a popsicle stick?
这是个矛
It's a spear.
还是一个酸橙味的矛
And it smells like lemon-lime,
土狼讨厌这个味道
A flavor coyotes hate.
你从哪儿知道这么多
Where are you getting your information?
还有多远
How much farther?
我想走远点
Well, I'd like to go far enough
远到看不见我们停车场里的车
that we can't still see our car in the parking lot.
我已经满嘴灰了
I'm getting dust in my mouth.
-你要对大自然心怀感恩 -是的
- You have to appreciate nature. - Yes.
这里很快就变成购物中心了
Soon, this will be the mall.
-那时候我再来吧 -我饿了
- I'll come then. - I'm hungry.
那估计下肚的是我们的心情
Oh, then I guess we'll be eating the mood.
我跟你完全无法交流
I don't get you at all.
我知道
I know.
那里是有派对吗
Oh, is that the party over there?
我不知道 我是个女人 记得吗
I don't know. I'm a woman, remember?
我的方向感极差
I have a terrible sense of direction.
允许我重申一下 我最大的错误就是
May I remind you that my big crime
给你做了松软的煎饼 行了不
was making you fluffy pancakes, okay?
你揪着这事喋喋不休的烦死了
I'm getting a little sick of you dwelling on this.
今天是母亲节 不是折磨日
It happens to be Mother's Day, not Martyr's Day.
米奇尔
Mitchell.
我错了 这对我来说是个敏感的事情
I'm sorry. It's just a sensitive issue for me.
行了
Okay.
同志最讨厌的事情莫过于
There's nothing gays hate more than when people...
-人们把我们当作女人 -人们把我们当作女人
- treat us like women. - Treat us like women.
我们是纯爷儿们
We're not.
我们不想去你们的婴儿洗礼
We don't want to go to your baby shower.
我们不会来"大姨妈"
We don't have a time of the month.
我们也不是粉色控
We don't love pink.
但是你喜爱粉色
Well, you love pink.
-不 是粉色喜欢我 -好吧
- No, pink loves me. - Okay.
-伙计们好啊 -你好 那是...
- Hey, guys! - Hey! So...
那是珍 老公叫瑞克 小孩叫迪亚哥
That's Jen, husband Rick, baby Diego.
我也不熟
I don't get it either.
珍 我来帮你
Hey, Jen. Let me help you with that.
瑞克 你好啊
Rick! How you doing?
我们周末应该多搞点团队活动
We should do play group on weekends more often.
有老公在身边帮忙就是好 对吧
It's nice to have the husbands around to help, right?
是啊 因为这让全世界都觉得
Oh, yeah, because that makes all the sense in the world --
你才是丈夫
You as the husband.
行了 她不是那意思
Stop it. That's not what she meant.
瞧瞧我们 我都可以把你那小身板给折断
Look at us. I could snap you like a twig.
够了 每隔段时间你就拿我的小身板出来说
Okay, every once in a while you say that thing about the twig,
-你要知道这让我很反感 -对不起
- And I need you to know that it bothers me. - Sorry.
好了 各位 母亲节快乐
Okay, everybody. Happy Mother's Day!
我代表所有的男士们
I know I speak for all the guys
感谢你们在我们下班风流快活的时候
when I say thank you for everything you do
所默默付出的一切
while we're off having affairs.
开玩笑的 我待会儿回家跪搓衣板
I'm kidding. I'll pay for that later.
我们先为妈妈和宝贝们拍张合影
Uh, let's get the moms and kids together for a picture!
完了 走 快走
No, let's go. Let's get out of here.
手推车不要了 赶紧跑
Leave the stroller and run.
小卡 停下 没人会叫你去
Cam, stop. No one's going to ask you to --
卡梅隆 快过来
Cameron, get on up here.
不用了吧 你们先拍吧
I don't know. You guys just go ahead.
-你可是名誉妈妈 -也不是啦
- You're an honorary mom! - Oh, I don't know.
好吧好吧
Uh, okay, all right.
-放手 -快过去吧
- Unhand me. - Get over there.
这不太合适吧
That's -- that's...
站近点 近点
Okay, tighten up, tighten up.
看这里 女士们
Up here, ladies!
太美了 再来一张 美女们
Beautiful. One more, gals.
谢谢女士们 非常感谢 太美了
Oh, thanks, ladies. Thanks so much. Perfect.
真棒 好了
Great. Okay.
是的 那肯定是毒葛
Yeah, that was definitely poison oak.
我觉得这皮疹在扩大
I think this rash is spreading.
曼尼 那不是皮疹
Manny, that's not a rash.
它变红是因为你抓的
It's red because you scratch it.
我只是想没话找话说
I just don't want my throat to close.
闭嘴不见得是件坏事
Wouldn't be the worst thing.
我太无聊了 我宁愿看书
I'm so bored, I'd rather be reading.
我也是 为了不无聊到麻木
I'm so bored, I chewed the last bug
我把刚飞进我嘴里的飞虫拿来磨牙
that flew in my mouth just to feel something.
我都无聊到跟你说话了
I'm so bored, I'm talking to you.
够了
Ugh! Okay!
在刚才的二十分钟里
For the last 20 minutes,
你们这些人只知道抱怨
all you people have done is whine!
你们有没有想过今天是母亲节
You would think on mother's day, at least,
至少 要说也说点好听的
You would have something nice to say --
-别说话 -怎么了
-Shh! - What?
我以为听到了土狼的声音 继续说吧
Thought I heard a coyote. Go ahead.
天啊 卢克 你个傻帽
God, Luke, you're such an idiot.
至少我看起来不像个傻帽
At least I don't look like an idiot.
-什么意思 -你的帽子
- What does that mean? - Your hat.
看起来像你头上飞的鸟 拉了一坨丑帽子
It's like you walked under a bird that poops ugly hats.
能不能注意语言文明
Can we watch the language?
我们也没有其它东西可以注意了
There's nothing else to watch.
闹够了没有
Enough complaining!
不要因为这一天没在沙滩度过
You can't bitch all day
就整天发牢骚
because you're not at the beach all day.
跟上
Come on.
不不不
No. No, no.
我要送我自己一个母亲节礼物
I-I'm giving myself a mother's day present.
孩子们 你们的徒步旅行结束了
Kids, your hike is over.
-好 -耶
- Yes! - Yeah!
不 不要得意
No! No, not happy.
-不好 很不好 -对
- Bad. Sad. - Mm.
我和歌洛莉亚要去完成
Gloria and I are gonna go finish
这次绝美的徒步旅行 你们就呆在这
this beautiful hike together while you sit here
好好思考你们是如何自私和无脑
and think about how selfish and thoughtless you've been.
我们走
Come on.
如果我们无脑 我们怎么能思考
If we're thoughtless, how can we think?
老娘没收你的水
You just lost your water.
我们走
Let's go.
你戴的什么玩意儿
What the hell are those?
洋葱护目镜 这样做饭就不流泪了
Onion goggles. No more tears when I cook.
欢迎来到21世纪 你应该去搞一副
Welcome to the 21st century. You should get a pair.
我也打算这么做
I was gonna suggest the same thing.
杰 你知道我们应该放些什么进去吗
Hey, Jay, you know what we should put in this?
-我们应该放 -不行
- We should add a da-- - No.
这是我妈妈的食谱
It's my mom's recipe.
上面说放什么就放什么
What it says on the page goes in the pot.
一样不能多 一样不能少
Nothing more, nothing less.
牛肉和香肠我要搅拌多久
Now, how long do I stir the beef and sausages?
读给我听
Read it to me.
牛肉和香肠搅拌5分钟
You should stir the beef and sausages for five minutes.
我要忍受你模仿
And how much longer do I have to listen
《朱莉娅·柴尔德印象厨房》到什么时候
to the Julia Child Impression?
一直到这个没意思了为止
For as long as it's still funny.
我觉得已经够了
I think the timer just went off on that.
不必这样吧
That was unnecessary.
这是什么
What's this?
什么
What?!
杰 在做好这个以后
Hey, Jay, maybe after this,
我们应该再做一道"完美妈妈"
we should make "the perfect mom."
我们只需要"一汤勺爱 一杯温暖
All we need is "a tablespoon of love, 1 cup of warmth,
以及一颗慈爱的心"
add one heart, softened."
你到底在说啥
What the hell are you talking about?
这个完美妈妈食谱
This recipe for the perfect mom,
杰·弗朗西斯·普里契特写于9岁
by Jay Francis Fritchett, age nine.
这个我都忘了
Geez, I forgot all about that.
我都不知道她把这个放食谱里面了
I didn't know she had that in there.
怎么了 弗朗西斯
What's that, Francis?
没什么
Nothing.
肉还要搅拌多久
How much longer on the meat?
我喜欢"做给一个小男孩吃"这句
I love the part about "serves one small boy."
太可爱了
That's adorable.
"175磅的温柔"
"175 pounds of tenderness."
她肯定爱死这个了 她很胖吗
She must have loved that. Big woman?
杰
Jay?
于是我就看见了
And that's when I saw it.
杰
Jay...
你是不是
Are...
-在哭 -没有
- Are you crying? - No!
都是洋葱惹的祸 靠 护目镜给我
It's the onions, damn it. Give me these.
你看什么看
What are you lookin' at?
没什么
Nothing.
这护目镜和你脸型很相称
Those really frame your face.
漂亮
Beautiful.
谢谢
Ay, thank you.
我不想让你批评我
Okay, I don't want you to judge me,
但是有些东西我不吐不快
but I have to say something.
有时候我真想揍我的孩子们
Sometimes, I want to punch my kids.
-你不会真心想这么做 -不 我真的想
- You don't mean that. - No, I do. I do.
上次就跟今天一样 他们非常讨厌
The last time they were horrible the way they were today,
他们正好站成了一排
They happened to be all lined up.
我那时禁不住想
And I couldn't help but think,
如果我打倒他们其中一个
"If I hit just one of them,
其余两个就会像多米诺骨牌一样倒下来
the rest would go down like dominos."
我知道
I know.
这样我就会失去
That would rob me of the pleasure
把他们一个一个打到的乐趣 但是
of hitting each one individually, but...
天啊 你可不能这么说自己的孩子
Oh, my god, you don't talk about your children this way.
行了吧 你知道曼尼有时候惹你生气
Oh, come on. You know Manny irritates you.
不 曼尼是我生命中最美好的存在
No. Manny is the best thing that ever happened to me.
我们之间有种特殊的纽带
We have a special bond.
对 纽带 我懂
Yes, bonds. I know.
但这不是现在我要说的
but that's not what I'm talking about now.
克莱尔 很长一段时间
Claire, for a long time,
都是我们母子俩相依为命
it was only the two of us.
我不能说任何关于这个孩子的坏话
I cannot say anything bad about that boy.
得了吧 歌洛莉亚
Give me a break, Gloria!
有孩子的人都知道
Anybody who's ever had a kid knows
在某些事情上他们会
that they can irritate the freaking life
让你的生活变得抓狂
out of you at some point.
我说的对吗
Am I right?
算了
Oh. Okay.
他很小气
He's persnickety.
-什么 -曼尼
- What? - Manny.
他太小气了 这让我抓狂
He's persnickety. It drives me up the wall.
很好 小气 良好的开始
Okay, persnickety. Good start.
他总是粘着我
He follows me around all the time.
有时候我会很享受
Sometimes I love it,
但有时侯我需要有自己的空间
but sometimes I need my own space.
说出这些事情并不意味着你是一个坏母亲
This does not make you a bad mother to admit these things.
还有那些诗 真的是太差劲了
And the poetry. It's not very good.
我终于第一次大声的说出来了
Ah. First time that I say that out loud.
不错
Okay.
真的是太差劲了
It's not very good!
我爱曼尼 但是 你知道的 有时我
I-I love Manny, but, you know, sometimes I --
要像个男孩子
Just be a boy!
去外面闯闯 踢踢球 偷偷东西什么的
Go outside. Kick a ball. Steal something.
感觉好极了
It feels so good!
或许你是感觉好极了
Maybe to you.
不 曼尼
No, Manny! Ay!
我说的是我以前认识的曼尼
I was talking about another Manny that I know long time ago!
恶魔[西班牙语]
Diablo!
曼尼
Manny!
你知道吗 远足死的人可比整个
You know, more people have died hiking
内战死的人多多了
than in the entire civil war?
好的 你是在哪本书上看到的
Ok, what book did you read that in?
书
Book?
醒醒吧 奶奶 现在是互联网时代
Wake up and smell the internet, grandma.
妈妈想要我们跟她道歉
You know mom's just gonn want us to apologize.
我们的确是毁了她的母亲节
Well, we did kind of ruin her mother's day.
不 是她自己毁掉的
No, she ruined her mother's day.
她把我们带到一个
She took us to a place
她明知我们不会喜欢的地方
she knew we wouldn't like.
我们就抱怨了那么几秒钟
And then we complain for like a second,
就成了坏人了吗
and we're the bad guys?
说得对
That's a good point.
你有没有感觉她是故意这么做的
You ever get the feeling she does this intentionally?
她为什么要这么做
Why would she do that?
-这样她就可以让我们感到愧疚 -没错
- So she can make us feel guilty. - Exactly.
下次我们决定要做什么的时候
And the next time we're choosing what to do,
她就又可以得逞了
she gets her way again.
以及下次 下下次
And the next time and the next time.
最终 每天都是母亲节
And eventually, it's mother's day every day.
妈妈真的是很聪明
Wow. Mom's really smart.
她可不及我
Well, not smarter than me.
这个嘛
Well...
我建议我们这次不跟她道歉
I say we don't apologize this time,
让她知道 我们跟她的小把戏耗上了
Let her know we're onto her little game.
我们可以改变整个家庭的运行模式
We could change the way this whole family operates.
好的 没有人会跟她道歉
Okay, so nobody says they're sorry.
明白了没 等她回来时嘴巴都闭紧了
Got it? Keep your mouths shut when she comes back.
如果她回得来的话
If she comes back.
杰在我面前泪眼婆娑
Jay teared up in front of me.
我从不知道他还有这么脆弱的一面
He'd never shown me that kind of vulnerability,
这让他很尴尬
and it embarrassed him.
我让那头骄傲的狮子感到惭愧
I'd shamed the proud lion.
唯一能做的
Only thing to do...
拥抱那头骄傲的狮子
...hug the proud lion.
我可能会被咬
Oh, I could get bit.
我或许会被抓伤
I could get scratched.
但你知道每头狮子心里都装着什么吗
But you know what's inside every lion?
一只小猫咪
A pussycat.
你给我滚远点
I need you to get away from me.
好的
Yep.
好的 我只说一次
Okay, I'm just gonna say this one time
然后就不提这茬了
so we can move on.
-这没什么 -明白
- It's okay. - Gotcha.
你知道"这"代表的是什么吗
You -- you know what "It" is?
是你的哭泣
It's you crying.
-我没哭 -你流泪了
- Which I didn't. - You teared up.
都说是洋葱惹的祸
It was the onions.
好的 好的
Okay, okay.
或许是我自动代入了你的角色多想了
Maybe I'm -- maybe I'm just putting myself in your place,
但是如果我碰巧发现儿时的东西
but if I came across something from my childhood,
而它又让我想起我母亲 我或许会泪水迷蒙
and it reminded me of my mom, I might get a little misty,
甚至还会想要找人倾诉
maybe even want to talk about it.
这里
Here.
太骄傲了
So proud.
他们给了我一束花 米奇尔
They offered me a bouquet, Mitchell.
你接受了
Which you accepted.
为什么你就不能站在我这边
Why can't you ever take my side?
他们把我当女人
They think of me as a woman!
小卡 不 拜托
Cam, no, come on.
我们是新型的家庭 你知道的
We're just a new type of family, you know?
他们还不知道怎么正确对待我们
They don't have the right vocabulary for us yet.
他们把其中的一个当做家庭中的母亲
They need one of us to be the mom.
为什么把我认作女人呢
So why does it have to be me?
我又没穿裙子
Do I wear a dress?
那是睡袍
That's a nightshirt!
又光滑又柔软
It's kind of satiny.
你是什么意思
What are you saying?
拜托 你知道的
Come on, you know.
不 我不知道
No. No, no, no. I don't know.
好吧 我想
All right, if I'm thinking about it,
如果咱俩个中 一定要选一个的话
of the two of us, if I had to pick,
我觉得在母亲这个角色上 你稍微地赢过我
I might say that you're slightly...Mom-er.
不好意思 你可以把那个球扔一下吗
Excuse me. Can you throw that ball?
我可以投球吗
Can I throw a ball?
-你认为我不能投球吗 -小卡
- You don't think I can throw a ball? - Cam
-住嘴 你别插话 -他不是那个意思
- No, no, no. - That's not what he said.
不 很显然 这位先生
No, apparently, this gentleman
认为我投不了球
doesn't think I can throw a ball.
他不是这个意思
Oh, that's not what he said.
你认为我投不了球 等着瞧
You think I can't throw a ball? Well, let's find out!
天啊 他年纪看起来挺大的
Oo god. He looks old.
对不起
Oh, sorry!
小卡 你的兰花指
Cam, hands.
对不起
Sorry!
看吧
There you go.
曼尼 我不是那个意思
Manny, I didn't mean any of it.
原谅我吧
Please forgive me!
我觉得我做不到吧 咱们快上车走吧
I don't think I can. Let's just get in the van.
对不起 我说话押韵了
Oh. Sorry for the rhyme.
我知道你有多讨厌我的诗
I know how you "hate my poetry."
不要再折磨我了
Please, stop my suffering!
你也对我说些很糟糕的话吧
Say something terrible about me
那我们就可以扯平了
so that we can be even like steven.
为什么我要对我爱的人说可怕的话呢
Why would I say something terrible to someone I love?
我诅咒自己的舌头
I curse my tongue!
我插一句
I'm gonna intervene here.
曼尼 我来说一下真实的情况
Manny, let's talk about what really happened, okay?
你妈妈的意思是你应该多出去玩玩球
Your mom said you should go out and throw a ball around.
那不可能是你第一次听到这种话吧
That can't be the first time you've heard that.
是的 但这些关于我的诗的话太伤人了
No. But there was some hurtful stuff said about my poetry.
你妈妈很后悔说了这些话
Which your mom regrets.
是的
I do!
所以 这就是家长要做的事
So? That's what parents are for.
有时候他们批评你 可以让你变得更强大
Sometimes they criticize because it helps make you stronger.
现在的孩子一直被夸奖
Kids these days get trophies just for showing up.
会导致什么结果呢
What's that gonna lead to?
三十多岁了还住在家里
A bunch of 30-year-olds living at home.
曼尼 你妈妈非常爱你
Manny, your mom loves you very much.
但是她也是个普通人
But she's a human being.
所以她也会想要小小地发泄一下
So she let off a little steam.
事实上 或许这对你们来说是好事
Honestly, it's probably a great thing for your relationship.
-我觉得我可以 -不要说了
- I guess I can - Stop.
我要让他知道真相
He needs to know the real truth.
曼尼 克莱尔觉得很糟糕
Manny, Claire was feeling bad
因为她想要打自己的孩子
because she wants to hit her own children,
所以我为了让她舒服些
So I tried to make her feel better
就胡说了一些关于你的坏话
by inventing terrible things about you.
你是说 你对我的诗没有意见
You mean you don't have a problem with my poetry?
没有 唯一的问题是
No, the only problem that I have
我怎么都听不够
is that I never have enough of it.
在任何什么方面 你都是个完美的孩子
You're the perfect kid in every way.
我的爱
Ay, mi amor
这亲情真健康
Wow. That's healthy.
好了 你回来了
Good. You're back.
咱们没事了吧
Are we done?
除非在这个特殊的节日里
Unless the you have something to say
你们有话要对带给你们生命的人说
to the person who gave you life on her special day.
-没有 -没有
- Nope. - I'm good.
我的宝贝卢克呢
My baby, Luke?
没有
No.
给你 这是什么
Here. What's this?
母亲节贺卡
Well, it's a mother's day card.
我知道了 别这样 好吧
And I know -- stop it! Okay.
小卡 这是曼尼给歌洛莉亚的贺卡
Cam, that was Gloria's card from Manny
我只是想让你知道
But I just wanted you to see
里面对母亲的定义
what its definition for "Mother" was on it.
是温暖 养育和支持
It's warm, nurturing, supportive.
或许别人认为你是家庭中母亲
You know, maybe when the world sees you as a mom --
不只是别人
Not just the world.
好吧 我也一样
Fine. Fine. Me too.
或许这正是我们所见的
But maybe this is what we're seeing,
我不觉得这是件坏事
And I don't know why that's such a bad thing.
它丝毫没减少你的男子气概 对吗
It certainly doesn't make you less of a man, right?
-也许你是对的 -没错
- Maybe you're right. - Yeah.
来吧 快加入他们的派对
Come on, let's join the party.
还有 小卡 把酒放下
And, Cam, put down the scotch.
你骗不了任何人
You're not fooling anyone.
这酒辣死了 天啊
It is so burn-y. Oh, my god.
快过来 大家都到桌子这儿来
Come on, people! Everybody to the table!
我只是很难接受这件事
It's just hard, you know?
好好的母亲节被毁了
Having your mother's day ruined.
我没有想到毁了它的人会是你 卢卡斯
I never thought it would be you, Lucas.
连想都别想
Don't even think about it.
但是她很伤心
But she's sad.
她伤心是因为她快输了
Sad she's losing.
她刚只是使出最拿手的煽情招数 试图打动你
She just hit you with her best shot.
咱们得保持强硬的态度
We need to stay strong.
-但是我感觉 -不许感觉
- But I feel-- - Don't feel!
去洗把脸 拿出你的男子气慨
Just go splash water on your face and man up!
现在我们就是你的妈妈
We're your mother now.
你今天跟我爸过得怎么样
How was your day with my dad?
说实话 很尴尬
Awkward, actually.
他 他小哭了一把
He, um... He cried a little.
-我爸 -嘘
- My dad?! - Shh!
-爸怎么了 -他哭了
- Dad what? - He cried.
没有 我没说他哭了
No, I didn't say he cried.
-谁哭了 -我爸 -别说了
- Who cried? - My dad. - Stop!
你为什么要让杰哭泣
Why would you make Jay sob like that?
我没让他哭泣
I didn't make him sob.
他哭是因为我发现
He teared up when I found this poem
他小时候写给妈妈的诗
he wrote for his mom as a boy.
-你们在感叹什么 -菲尔看见爸哭了
- What is "Ohh"? - Phil saw dad cry.
杰想妈妈了
Jay misses his mama.
-你们都给我住嘴 -有人饿了吗
- Everybody, stop! - Is anybody hungry?
-怎么了 -你为了你妈妈哭了
- What? - You cried for your mommy?
妈的 我才没哭
Oh, crap. I did not.
你哭了 菲尔刚才告诉我们的
Yes, Phil just told us--
没有 那不是真的 她说谎
No, that's not true. She's a liar.
你这算怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
我知道如果我因为我妈
Look, I know you would all be so happy
而情绪失控 你们会很高兴
if you thought I had some big emotional moment
但是我没有
about my mom, but I didn't.
所以说你并不想念你妈妈咯
So you don't miss your mom?
我当然想她 她是个杰出的女性
Of course I do. She was a great lady.
而且她也给我留下一份完美无比的酱料配方
And she also left me a fantastic recipe for sauce,
现在酱都要冷掉了
which now is getting cold.
所以我们能用餐了吗
So can we please eat?
-赞成 -去拿点酒来
- Hear, hear! - Just grab some wine.
我的上帝 闻闻看
Oh, my Gosh, smell that.
这味道就跟以前在奶奶家闻的一样
It smells like grandma's house.
你们还记得那个味道啊
Hey, you guys remember that?
我记得我第一次切意大利面
I remember the first time I cut spaghetti.
-不行 -奶奶就那样跟我说不行
- Eh-eh! - That's what she did! Eh-eh!
没错 不 你不能切意大利面
Yeah, no, you can't cut spaghetti.
她教会我要转着吃
She taught me to twirl.
所以是她把你转弯的吧
Oh, so she's the one.
没错 她很严格
Yeah, she was tough.
我记得有个联赛的小教练
I remember I had this little league coach.
有一次在一场比赛结束之后
And one time after a game,
他因为某事而痛斥我
he was laying into me about something.
具体是什么我忘了
I don't remember.
但我妈从看台那冲出来
But mom comes charging out of the stands.
她径直走到教练那
She goes right up to the guy --
我是说 面对面 你眼望我眼那种
I mean, face to face, nose to nose --
然后她对他说 "我告诉你
And she says to him, "Let me tell you something --
"没有人 真的没有人
"Nobody, and I mean nobody,
"能这么吼我的
"Yells at my little
儿子"
Boy."
我的天 他又哭了
Oh, my god! It's happening again!
没关系 杰 男人哭吧不是罪
It's okay, Jay. Let it out.
-尽情宣泄吧 -人只有一个妈妈
- Let it out. - You only get one mom.
我很抱歉 妈
I'm sorry, mom!
我也是
Me too!
一瓶红酒 一瓶 什么状况
A bottle of red, a bottle of -- what?!
真好 到底是谁不够强硬
Oh, yeah, and I'm the weak one.
米奇尔
Mitchell?
我就不用了
Oh, I'm good.
菲尔
Phil!
-爸 -过来 宝贝儿
- Dad! - Come on, honey!
对不起
I'm sorry.
-讨厌 从我身上下去 -对不起嘛
- Ew, get off of me! - I'm sorry!
爸爸
Dada!
我觉得她是在叫你
Oh, I think she's calling you.
想都别想
Don't even try.
明天早晨我还有陶瓷课
I have that pottery class in the morning.
杰 咱们去睡觉吧
Jay, let's go to bed.
马上就来
Be right up.
真他妈失策
Son of a bitch.